Kamilhakim Sabarudin

Final Year Undergraduate

Phone: +44 (0) 74 9332 4269 E-mail: kamilhakim@zoho.com LinkedIn: in/kamilhakim-sabarudin

Summary

Final year computer science student with a technology internship experience at global bank Barclays UK. Experienced in turning data into insights in Python and writing software in Java. A keen team player with excellent communication and collaboration skills. Currently improving knowledge in Data Science and Natural Language Processing.

Education

Lancaster University

Bachelor of Science (Hons.) in Computer Science; Grade 2:1

Lancaster, United Kingdom Oct 2021 – Jun 2024 (Exp.)

Relevant Coursework:

- Data Structures Gained foundational skills in data structures, focusing on efficient data manipulation, storage, and handling of diverse data formats.
- Databases Acquired skills in SQL and NoSQL query, Python integration and structured database design for effective use in database operations and data warehouse.
- Software Design Developed proficiency in software development lifecycle and implementing agile methodologies and best practices in software engineering.

Kolej MARA Banting

Selangor, Malaysia

International Baccalaureate Diploma; Points 41/45

Jul 2019 - May 2022

Subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, English, Malay, Information Technology in A Global Society.

Work Experience

Barclays Bank UK

Knutsford, United Kingdom

Technology Developer Summer Intern

Jun 2023 – Aug 2023

- Worked in Customer Care Technology team. Supported the implementation of a new system by analysing failure scenarios in Python and SQL to recommend areas of improvement.
- Identified a major risk which led to a system improvement that eliminates customer data loss and improve customer retention.
- Developed a colleague-facing risk management system in Microsoft Power Platform to support centralised data collection and improve risk visibility.

Shopee Malaysia

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Data Entry (Contract)

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

- Verified and processed 700 background check reports within two weeks, reduced delivery time from 7 days to 2 days.
- Enhanced the data integrity and accuracy through establishing standards and automating checks in Excel.

Universiti Putra Malaysia

Selangor, Malaysia

Research Trainee

Dec 2019

Volunteering & Activities

Treasurer Lancaster Debating Union

Jun 2022 – Present

Served as a member of the executive committee, playing a critical role in managing the club's expenses to allow more activities to be conducted.

Student Representative Faculty of Science and Technology

Oct 2021 – Jun 2022

Facilitate improvement in student experience by attending weekly meetings with the faculty and contribute to resolving issues faced by students.

Member PULMA 2.0 Fundraise

Jan 2020 - Mar 2021

Raised MYR3000 (GBP530) fund in a team for an indigenous community in Pulau Mabul, Sabah, Malaysia to provide maintenance of the local school.

Programming Skills

Languages: Python / Java / JavaScript / C, C#

Software and Utilities: Git / PostgreSQL / MongoDB / TensorFlow / .Net Core 6 / REST API / GraphQL

Certifications: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)